My work is play.
يتمحور عملي حول اللعب.
And I play when I design.
فأنا في الواقع ألعب عندما أصمم
I even looked it up in the dictionary, to make sure
حتى أنني بحثت عن معنى الكلمة في القاموس، كي أكون متأكدة
that I actually do that,
بأن ذلك هو ما أقوم به بالفعل.
and the definition of play,
تعرف كلمة لعب بأنها:
number one, was engaging in a childlike
أولا: الانخراط في نشاط أو
activity or endeavor,
عمل طفولي،
and number two was gambling.
وثانيا: المقامرة.
And I realize I do both
أدركت حينها بأنني أقوم بكلا الفعلين
when I'm designing.
عندما أصمم.
I'm both a kid and I'm gambling all the time.
فأنا طفلة ومقامرة طوال الوقت.
And I think that if you're not,
وأعتقد أنه اذا لم تكن كذلك،
there's probably something inherently wrong
فمن المحتمل أن ثمة خطأ
with the structure or the situation you're in,
في التركيب أو الوضع الذي أنت فيه،
if you're a designer.
اذا كنت مصمما.
But the serious part is what threw me,
ولكن الجانب الجاد هو ما حيرني،
and I couldn't quite get a handle
ولم أستطع فهمه
on it until I remembered an essay.
الا عندما تذكرت مقالا.
And it's an essay I read 30 years ago.
وهو مقال قرأته قبل 30 عاما.
It was written by Russell Baker,
المقال كتبه راسل باكر,
who used to write an "Observer" column in the New York Times.
الذي اعتاد كتابة عمود صحفي "المراقب" في النيويورك تايمس.
He's a wonderful humorist. And I'm going to read you
وهو كاتب هزلي رائع. وأنا سأقرأ عليكم
this essay,
المقال
or an excerpt from it
أو مقتطفا منه
because it really hit home for me.
لأنه في حقيقة الأمر كان له تأثير علي.
Here is a letter of friendly advice.
هذه رسالة نصح حميمة.
Be serious, it says.
تقول, كن جادا.
What it means, of course, is, be solemn.
وما تعنيه هذه الكلمة بالطبع هو أن تتحلى بالرصانة
Being solemn is easy.
أن تكون رصينا هو أمر سهل.
Being serious is hard.
أن تكون جادا فهذا أمر صعب.
Children almost always begin by being serious,
الأطفال يبدأون حياتهم عادة بجدية
which is what makes them so entertaining
مما يجعلهم غاية في التسلية
when compared with adults as a class.
مقارنة بالبالغين.
Adults, on the whole, are solemn.
الكبار في المجمل رصينون.
In politics, the rare candidate who is serious,
في السياسة، المرشح السياسي الذي يتمتع بالجدية،
like Adlai Stevenson,
مثل أدلاي ستيفنسون
is easily overwhelmed by one who is solemn, like Eisenhower.
يهيمن عليه بسهولة شخص رصين مثل أيزنهاور.
That's because it is hard for most people
سبب ذلك هو أن أغلب الناس يجدون صعوبة
to recognize seriousness, which is rare,
في ادراك الجدية التي هي صفة نادرة
but more comfortable to endorse solemnity,
ولكنهم أكثر ارتياحا في اعتماد الرصانة
which is commonplace.
التي تعتبر مألوفة.
Jogging, which is commonplace,
ممارسة اليوغا، التي تعد مألوفة
and widely accepted as good for you, is solemn.
ومقبولة على نطاق واسع كشيء ايجابي للفرد، هي عمل رصين.
Poker is serious.
لعبة البوكر جدية.
Washington, D.C. is solemn.
واشنطن العاصمة رصينة.
New York is serious.
نيويورك جدية.
Going to educational conferences to tell you anything
الذهاب لمؤتمر تعليمي يتناول أي شيء
about the future is solemn.
عن المستقبل، هو أمر رصين.
Taking a long walk by yourself,
المشي لمسافات طويلة وحيدا،
during which you devise a foolproof scheme for robbing Tiffany's,
تراجع خلالها خطة محكمة للسطو على محلات تيفاني،
is serious.
هو أمر جاد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, when I apply Russell Baker's definition
والآن، عندما أطبق تعريف راسل بيكر
of solemnity or seriousness to design,
للرصانة أو الجدية على التصميم،
it doesn't necessarily make any particular point about quality.
فإن التطبيق لا يثبت بالضرورة أي نقطة محددة عن الجودة.
Solemn design is often important and very effective design.
التصميم الرصين هو عادة تصميم مهم وفعال جدا.
Solemn design is also socially correct,
التصميم الرصين هو أيضا صحيح اجتماعيا,
and is accepted by appropriate audiences.
ومقبول بالنسبة للجمهور المعني.
It's what right-thinking designers
وهو ما يسعى اليه المصممون المحافظون
and all the clients are striving for.
ومجمل العملاء كهدف يجب الوصول اليه.
Serious design, serious play,
التصميم الجاد,اللعب الجاد,
is something else.
شيء آخر.
For one thing, it often happens
فهو على سبيل المثال، غالبا ما يحدث
spontaneously, intuitively,
بشكل عفوي, بديهي,
accidentally or incidentally.
عرضي او غير عرضي,
It can be achieved out of innocence, or arrogance,
ويمكن أن يكون وليد البراءة أو الغطرسة,
or out of selfishness, sometimes out of carelessness.
أو الأنانية، وأحيانا وليد عدم الاكتراث.
But mostly, it's achieved through all those kind of crazy
ولكن في أغلب الأحيان يتحقق من خلال كل تلك الاصناف المجنونة
parts of human behavior that
المكونة للسلوك البشري والتي
don't really make any sense.
حقيقة لا تشكل اي معنى.
Serious design is imperfect.
التصميم الجاد غير كامل.
It's filled with the kind of craft laws that come from something being
فهو ينبثق عن قوانين البراعة النابعة من شيء
the first of its kind.
يعتبر الاول من نوعه.
Serious design is also -- often -- quite unsuccessful
التصميم الجاد هو ايضا -غالبا- غير ناجح الى حد بعيد
from the solemn point of view.
من وجهة النظر الجادة.
That's because the art of serious play
وذلك لان فن التصميم الجاد
is about invention, change, rebellion -- not perfection.
يتمحور حول الابداع، التغيير، الثورة- وليس الكمال.
Perfection happens during solemn play.
الكمال يحدث في مرحلة التصميم الرصين.
Now, I always saw design careers
والان، أنظر إلى مهن التصميم
like surreal staircases.
كسلالم سريالية
If you look at the staircase, you'll see
اذا نظرت مثلا الى السلالم، فسترى
that in your 20s the risers are very high
انه عندما تكون في العشرينيات فان الدرجات عالية
and the steps are very short,
ودرجات السلم قصيرة جدا
and you make huge discoveries.
مما يجعلك تقوم باكتشافات كبيرة.
You sort of leap up very quickly in your youth.
تقوم نوعا ما بقفزات كبيرة في شبابك.
That's because you don't know anything and you have a lot to learn,
وذلك لانك لا تعرف شيئا ولديك اشياء كثيرة لتتعلمها,
and so that anything you do is a learning experience
لذا كل شيء تعمله هو نوع من التجربة التعليمية
and you're just jumping right up there.
وما تقوم به هو فقط القفز الى تلك النقطة.
As you get older, the risers get shallower
عندما يتقدم بك العمر، يصبح السلم أقصر
and the steps get wider,
ودرجات السلم أعرض
and you start moving along at a slower pace
وتبدأ بالتحرك بوتيرة أبطأ
because you're making fewer discoveries.
لأنك تقوم باكتشافات محدودة
And as you get older and more decrepit,
وعندما يتقدم بك العمر وتصبح أكثر ضعفا
you sort of inch along on this
فإنك نوعا ما تسير على
sort of depressing, long staircase,
سلم طويل ومحبط
leading you into oblivion.
يقودك إلى النسيان
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I find it's actually getting really hard to be serious.
وأجد في الواقع أن المرء يجد صعوبة كبيرة في أن يكون جادا
I'm hired to be solemn, but I find more and more
الناس يوظفونني لأكون رصينة لكنني أجد بأنني
that I'm solemn when I don't have to be.
رصينة عندما لا أضطر لأكون كذلك
And in my 35 years of working experience,
وعلى مدى سنوات خبرتي العملية التي تمتد لخمس وثلاثين عاما
I think I was really serious four times.
أعتقد بأنني كنت جادة أربع مرات
And I'm going to show them to you now,
وسأعرض هذه الحالات الأربع عليكم الآن
because they came out of very specific conditions.
لأنها انبثقت عن ظروف محددة
It's great to be a kid.
من الرائع أن يكون المرء طفلا
Now, when I was in my early 20s,
حسنا، عندما كنت في العشرينات من عمري
I worked in the record business, designing record covers for CBS Records,
عملت في صناعة الاسطوانات أصمم أغلفة الاسطوانات لشركة سي بي اس ريكوردز
and I had no idea what a great job I had.
ولم أكن أدرك الوظيفة الرائعة التي حظيت بها
I thought everybody had a job like that.
كنت أعتقد أن الجميع لديهم وظيفة مثل وظيفتي
And what --
وكانت
the way I looked at design and the way I looked at the world was,
الطريقة التي أنظر بها إلى التصميم والطريقة التي أنظر بها إلى العالم
what was going on around me
هي ما يدور حولي
and the things that came at the time I walked into design
وكانت الأشياء التي واجهتها عندما دخلت عالم التصميم
were the enemy.
هي العدو
I really, really, really hated
كنت أكره إلى درجة كبيرة
the typeface Helvetica.
الخط الطباعي هيلفيتيكا
I thought the typeface Helvetica
كنت أرى هذا الخط
was the cleanest, most boring, most fascistic,
على أنه الأكثر مللا وفاشية
really repressive typeface,
وقمعا
and I hated everything that was designed in Helvetica.
وكرهت كل ما كان مصمما باستخدام هذا الخط الطباعي
And when I was in
وعندما كنت في
my college days,
أيام دراستي الجامعية
this was the sort of design
كان هذا النوع من التصميم
that was fashionable and popular.
هو الرائج والشائع
This is actually quite a lovely book jacket by Rudy de Harak,
هذا في الواقع غلاف كتاب رائع لرودي دي هارا
but I just hated it, because it was designed with Helvetica,
لكنني كرهته لأنه كان مصمما باستخدام الخط هيلفيتيكا
and I made parodies about it.
وصممت محاكاة للسخرية منه
I just thought it was, you know, completely boring.
كنت أعتقد بأنه كان مملا تماما
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So -- so, my goal in life
لذا فإن هدفي في الحياة
was to do stuff that wasn't made out of Helvetica.
كان أن أصمم أشياء بدون استخدام الخط هيلفيتيكا
And to do stuff that wasn't made out of Helvetica
وكان ابتكار أشياء غير مصممة باستخدام الخط هيلفيتيكا
was actually kind of hard because you had to find it.
صعبا نوعا ما لأن ذلك كان يعني أن تبحث
And there weren't a lot of books about the history of design
ولم تكن هنالك كتب كثيرة عن تاريخ التصميم
in the early 70s. There weren't --
في أوائل السبعينيات. لم يكن هنالك
there wasn't a plethora of design publishing.
لم تكن هنالك وفرة في منشورات التصميم
You actually had to go to antique stores. You had to go to Europe.
كان عليك أن تذهب إلى محلات التحف وكان عليك أن تذهب إلى أوروبا
You had to go places and find the stuff.
كان على المرء أن يزور أماكن ويجد الأشياء
And what I responded to was, you know,
وما أعجبني كان
Art Nouveau, or deco,
الخط الطباعي آرت نوفو أو ديكو
or Victorian typography,
أو الفكتوري
or things that were just completely not Helvetica.
أو الأشياء التي لم تكن مصممة بالكامل بالخط هيلفيتيكا
And I taught myself design this way,
وعلمت نفسي التصميم بهذه الطريقة
and this was sort of my early years,
وكان هذا ما شكل سنواتي الأولى
and I used these things
واستعملت هذه الأشياء
in really goofy ways
بطرق غريبة
on record covers and in my design.
على أغلفة الاسطوانات وفي تصاميمي
I wasn't educated. I just sort of
لم أكن مثقفة بل كل ما عملته
put these things together.
كان وضع هذه الأشياء مع بعضها البعض
I mixed up Victorian designs with pop,
مزجت التصاميم الفكتورية مع البوب
and I mixed up Art Nouveau with something else.
ومزجت آرت نوفو مع شيء آخر
And I made these very lush,
فحصلت على أغلفة اسطوانات غنية
very elaborate record covers,
ومحكمة التصميم
not because I was being a post-modernist or a historicist --
ليس لأنني كنت عصرية أو غير عصرية
because I didn't know what those things were.
لأنني لم أكن أعلم حقيقة هذه الأشياء
I just hated Helvetica.
بل لمجرد أنني كنت أكره الخط هيلفيتيكا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And that kind of passion
وهذا النوع من العاطفة
drove me into very serious play,
قادني إلى اللعب الجاد
a kind of play I could never do now
ذلك النوع من اللعب الذي لا أستطيع أن أمارسه الآن
because I'm too well-educated.
لأنني مثقفة ومتعلمة إلى حد بعيد
And there's something wonderful about
وثمة أمر رائع
that form of youth,
يحيط بذلك الشكل من الشباب
where you can let yourself
عندما تسمح لنفسك
grow and play, and be
بالنمو واللعب
really a brat, and then accomplish things.
وأن تكون مزعجا وتنجز أشياء
By the end of the '70s, actually,
بنهاية السبعينيات في الواقع
the stuff became known.
أصبحت تصاميمي معروفة
I mean, these covers appeared all over the world,
وأعني بأن هذه الأغلفة ظهرت في جميع أرجاء العالم
and they started winning awards,
وبدأت تحصل على جوائز
and people knew them.
وعرفها الناس
And I was suddenly a post-modernist,
وأصبحت فجأة عصرية
and I began a career as -- in my own business.
وبدأت مهنة تخصني وحدي
And first I was praised for it, then criticized for it,
في البدء تلقيت الثناء ثم النقد
but the fact of the matter was, I had become solemn.
لكن في حقيقة الأمر أنني أصبحت رصينة
I didn't do what I think
لم أكن أصنع ما اعتقدت
was a piece of serious work again for about 14 years.
بأنه جزء من اللعب الجاد مرة أخرى لمدة 14 عاما تقريبا
I spent most of the '80s being quite solemn,
قضيت أغلب الثمانينات وأنا رصينة جدا
turning out these sorts of designs
أقدم تلك الأنواع من التصاميم
that I was expected to do
التي كان متوقعا مني تقديمها
because that's who I was,
لأنها تعكس ما أنا عليه
and I was living in this cycle of going from serious to solemn
وكنت أعيش هذه الدورة التي أنتقل فيها من التصاميم الجدية إلى الرصينة
to hackneyed to dead, and getting rediscovered all over again.
إلى المبتذلة إلى الخالية من الحياة وإعادة الاكتشاف من جديد
So, here was the second condition
وهذه هي الحالة الثانية
for which I think I accomplished some serious play.
التي أعتقد أنني حققت فيها بعض اللعب الجاد
There's a Paul Newman movie
هنالك فيلم لبول نيومان
that I love called "The Verdict."
الذي أحببت أن أطلق عليه "الحكم"
I don't know how many of you have seen it, but it's a beaut.
لا أعلم كم منكم رأى الفيلم لكنه كان فيلما رائعا
And in the movie, he plays
وفي الفيلم يلعب بول نيومان
a down-and-out lawyer
دور محامي معدم
who's become an ambulance chaser.
أصبح يبحث عن عملاء
And he's taken on --
وتولى
he's given, actually -- a malpractice suit to handle
في الواقع أعطي قضية اهمال ليترافع فيها
that's sort of an easy deal,
قضية سهلة
and in the midst of trying to connect the deal,
وفي خضم عملية ابرام الصفقة
he starts to empathize
بدأ يتعاطف
and identify with his client,
مع عميله
and he regains his morality and purpose,
وبدأ يستعيد أخلاقه وأهدافه
and he goes on to win the case.
وربح القضية
And in the depth of despair,
وفي قمة يأسه
in the midst of the movie, when it looks like he can't pull this thing off,
في منتصف الفيلم عندما يبدو أنه لن يتمكن من النجاح
and he needs this case,
وهو في حاجة إلى هذه القضية
he needs to win this case so badly.
وفي حاجة إلى أن يربح هذه القضية بشدة
There's a shot of Paul Newman alone,
تظهر لقطة لبول نيومان يجلس وحيدا
in his office, saying,
في مكتبه ويقول
"This is the case. There are no other cases.
هذه هي القضية. ليست هنالك قضايا أخرى
This is the case. There are no other cases."
هذه هي القضية. ليست هنالك قضايا أخرى.
And in that moment of
وفي تلك اللحظة
desire and focus,
من الرغبة والتركيز
he can win.
يمكنه الفوز
And that is a wonderful
وهذا وضع رائع
position to be in to create some serious play.
لابتكار اللعب الجاد
And I had that moment in 1994
مررت بتلك اللحظة في العام 1994
when I met a theater director
عندما التقيت بمدير مسرحي
named George Wolfe,
يدعى جورج وولف
who was going to have me design
والذي أراد مني تصميم
an identity for the New York Shakespeare Festival,
هوية لمهرجان شكسبير في نيويورك
then known,
والذي كان معروفا في ذلك الوقت
and then became the Public Theater.
وأصبح المسرح العام
And I began getting immersed
وبدأت انهمك
in this project
في هذا المشروع
in a way I never was before.
بطريقة لم أعهدها من قبل
This is what theater advertising looked like at that time.
هذا ما كان يبدو عليه اعلان المسرح في ذلك الوقت
This is what was in the newspapers and in the New York Times.
هذا ما كان موجودا في الصحف وفي جريدة النيويورك تايمز
So, this is sort of a comment on the time.
لذا فهذا نوع من التعليق على تلك الفترة
And the Public Theater actually had much better advertising than this.
وكان للمسرح العام في الواقع اعلان أفضل بكثير من هذا
They had no logo and no identity,
لم يكن لديهم شعار أو هوية
but they had these very iconic posters
لكن كان لديهم هذه الملصقات الأيقونية
painted by Paul Davis.
المرسومة من قبل بول ديفيس
And George Wolf had taken over from another director
واستلم جورج وولف مهامه من مدير آخر
and he wanted to change the theater,
وأراد أن يغير المسرح
and he wanted to make it urban and loud
أراد أن يجعله حضريا وصاخبا
and a place that was inclusive.
ومكانا شاملا
So, drawing on my love of typography,
وبناء على حبي للفن الطباعي
I immersed myself into this project.
انهمكت في هذا المشروع
And what was different about it was the totality of it,
وما كان مختلفا في هذا المشروع شموليته
was that I really became the voice, the visual voice, of a place
وأنني أصبحت الصوت المرئي لمكان
in a way I had never done before,
بطريقة لم أعهدها من قبل
where every aspect --
حيث أن كل جانب من جوانب المشروع
the smallest ad, the ticket, whatever it was --
أصغر اعلان والتذاكر وكل شيء
was designed by me.
كان من تصميمي
There was no format.
لم يكن هنالك صيغة
There was no in-house department that these things were pushed to.
لم يكن هنالك جانب محدد تنتمي إليه هذه الأشياء
I literally for three years made everything --
على مدى ثلاث سنوات كل شيء كان من تصميمي
every scrap of paper, everything online,
كل قصاصة ورقية وكل شيء على الانترنت
that this theater did.
كل شيء فعله هذا المسرح
And it was the only job,
وكانت هي المهمة الوحيدة
even though I was doing other jobs.
رغم أنني كنت أقوم بمهام أخرى
I lived and breathed it in a way I haven't
عشت المهمة وتنفستها بطريقة غير مسبوقة لي
with a client since.
مع أي من عملائي
It enabled me to really express myself and grow.
مكنتني هذه المهمة من التعبير عن نفسي حقا ومن أن أكبر
And I think that you know
وأعتقد أنكم تعلمون
when you're going to be given this position,
عندما تمنحون هذا المنصب
and it's rare, but when you get it and you have this opportunity,
وهذا أمر نادر، لكن عندما تحصلون عليه وتكون لديكم الفرصة
it's the moment of serious play.
فإنها لحظة اللعب الجاد
I did these things, and I still do them.
فعلت هذه الأمور وما أزال أفعلها
I still work for the Public Theater.
لا أزال أعمل للمسرح العام
I'm on their board, and
أنا أنتمي لطاقم عملهم
I still am involved with it.
لا أزال معنية بالأمر
The high point of the Public Theater, I think, was in 1996,
كانت الذروة للمسرح العام في العام 1996
two years after I designed it,
بعد عامين من تصميمي له
which was the "Bring in 'da Noise, Bring in 'da Funk" campaign
عندما كانت الحملة تحت شعار "المزيد من الصخب المزيد من الموسيقى"
that was all over New York.
وكانت الحملة في جميع أرجاء نيويورك
But something happened to it, and what happened to it was,
لكن شيء ما حدث للحملة
it became very popular.
أنها أصبحت شائعة جدا
And that is a kiss of death for something serious
وهذا كان مثل قبلة الموت لشيء جاد
because it makes it solemn.
لأنها تجعله أمر رصين
And what happened was
وما حدث كان متعلقا بالهوية
that New York City, to a degree,
حيث أن نيويورك إلى حد ما
ate my identity
التهمت هويتي
because people began to copy it.
لأن الناس بدأوا ينسخونها
Here's an ad in the New York Times
هذا اعلان في جريدة النيويورك تايمز
somebody did for a play called "Mind Games."
صممه شخص ما لمسرحية تدعى "ألغاز العقل"
Then "Chicago" came out, used similar graphics,
ثم مسرحية شيكاغو وكان تصميمها يحوي المزيد من الصور
and the Public Theater's identity was just totally eaten and taken away,
حينئذ أصبحت هوية المسرح العام منسية ومهملة تماما
which meant I had to change it.
مما اضطرني إلى تغييرها
So, I changed it so that every season was different,
فقمت بتغييرها بحيث كل موسم كان له هوية مختلفة
and I continued to do these posters,
واستمريت في تصميم الملصقات
but they never had the seriousness
لكنها لم تكن تتحلى بالجدية
of the first identity
التي اتسمت بها الهوية الأولى
because they were too individual, and they didn't have that heft
لأنها كانت فردية ولم تكن تتحلى بالقيمة
of everything being the same thing.
بأن كل شيء يتسم بنفس المعيار
Now -- and I think since the Public Theater,
الآن وأعتقد منذ عملي في المسرح العام
I must have done more than a dozen
قمت بتصميم العديد من
cultural identities for major institutions,
الهويات الثقافية لمؤسسات كبرى
and I don't think I ever -- I ever
ولا أعتقد بأنني اعتنقت مطلقا
grasped that seriousness again --
ذلك النوع من الجدية ثانية
I do them for very big, important institutions
أقوم بهذه التصاميم لمؤسسات كبيرة وهامة
in New York City.
في مدينة نيويورك
The institutions are solemn,
المؤسسات رصينة
and so is the design.
وكذلك التصميم
They're better crafted than the Public Theater was,
تصاميمها أكثر حرفية من تصميم المسرح العام
and they spend more money on them, but I think
وتنفق أموال أكثر عليها لكنني أعتقد
that that moment comes and goes.
أن تلك اللحظة تأتي وتذهب
The best way to accomplish serious design --
الطريقة المثلى لتحقيق تصميم جاد
which I think we all have the opportunity to do --
وهو ما أعتقد أننا جميعا قادرون على فعله
is to be totally and completely unqualified for the job.
أن تكون غير مؤهل تماما للمهمة
That doesn't happen very often,
وهذا لا يحدث كثيرا
but it happened to me in the year 2000,
لكن هذا الأمر حدث لي في العام 2000
when for some reason or another,
لسبب معين
a whole pile of different architects
مجموعة كبيرة من المهندسين المعماريين
started to ask me to design
بدأت تطلب مني تصميم
the insides of theaters with them,
الجزء الداخلي من المسارح معهم
where I would take environmental graphics and work them into buildings.
حيث آخذ الرسوم البيئية وأحولها إلى مباني
I'd never done this kind of work before.
لم أمارس هذا النوع من العمل من قبل
I didn't know how to read an architectural plan,
لم أكن أستطيع قراءة المخططات المعمارية
I didn't know what they were talking about,
لم أكن أعلم ما الذي يقصدونه بالضبط
and I really couldn't handle the fact that a job --
ولم أستطع أن أستوعب حقيقة أن مهمة معينة
a single job -- could go on for four years
مهمة مفردة يمكن أن تستغرق أربع سنوات
because I was used to immediacy in graphic design,
لأنني كنت معتادة على الفورية في التصميم الجرافيكي
and that kind of attention to detail
وهذا النوع من الاهتمام بالتفاصيل
was really bad for somebody like me, with ADD.
كان أمرا سيئا لشخص مثلي
So, it was a rough -- it was a rough go,
لذا كانت الانطلاقة صعبة
but I fell in love with this process
لكني وقعت في حب العملية برمتها
of actually integrating graphics into architecture
في دمج التصاميم الجرافيكية في الهندسة المعمارية
because I didn't know what I was doing.
لأنني لم أكن أعلم ما أكنت أقوم به
I said, "Why can't the signage be on the floor?"
كنت أقول: "لماذا لا تكون اللافتات على الأرض؟"
New Yorkers look at their feet.
بحيث ينظر مواطنو نيويروك إلى أقدامهم
And then I found that actors and actresses
وعندها وجدت الممثلين والممثلات
actually take their cues from the floor,
يقرأون جمل أدوارهم من الأرض
so it turned out that these sorts of sign systems
وعندها تبين أن هذا النوع من الإشارات
began to make sense.
بدأ يصبح ذو مغزى
They integrated with the building in really peculiar ways.
وبدأت تندمج مع المباني بطرق خاصة
They ran around corners,
كانت اللافتات تدور مع زوايا المباني
they went up sides of buildings,
تتدرج إلى أعلى المباني
and they melded into the architecture.
وتتحد مع الهندسة المعمارية
This is Symphony Space on 90th Street and Broadway,
هذه بناية "سيمفوني سبايس" في شارع 90 وبرودواي
and the type is interwoven into the stainless steel
والخط متشابك مع الحديد غير القابل للصدأ
and backlit with fiber optics.
ومضاء من الخلفية بألياف بصرية
And the architect, Jim Polshek,
والمهندس المعماري جيم بولشيك
essentially gave me a canvas
قدم لي قماش القنب
to play typography out on.
لأضع الكتابة عليه
And it was serious play.
وكان هذا لعبا جادا
This is the children's museum in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania,
هذا هو متحف الأطفال في بيتسبيرغ، بينسلفانيا
made out of completely inexpensive materials.
مصنوع من مواد غير مكلفة
Extruded typography that's backlit with neon.
مندمج مع خطوط مضاءة بالنيون
Things I never did before, built before.
أشياء لم أقم بها أو ببنائها من قبل
I just thought they'd be kind of fun to do.
كنت أعتقد أنه من المرح أن أقوم بها
Donors' walls made out of Lucite.
جدران المتبرعين من الزجاج العضوي
And then, inexpensive signage.
ولافتة غير مكلفة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I think my favorite of these
أعتقد أن التصميم المفضل لي
was this little job in Newark, New Jersey.
كان المهمة الصغيرة في نيوارك-نيوجيرسي
It's a performing arts school.
في كلية فنون
This is the building that -- they had no money,
هذه هي البناية ولم يكن لديهم المال اللازم
and they had to recast it, and they said,
وكان عليهم إعادة صبها وقالوا
if we give you 100,000 dollars, what can you do with it?
إذا أعطيناك 100،000 دولار ماذا يمكن أن تقدمي لنا
And I did a little Photoshop job on it, and I said,
وقمت بمهمة صغيرة على الفوتوشوب وقلت
Well, I think we can paint it.
أعتقد أننا يمكن أن نطليها
And we did. And it was play.
وهذا ما قمنا به. كان لعبا
And there's the building. Everything was painted --
وها هي البناية كل شيء تم طلائه
typography over the whole damn thing,
الخط الطباعي على كامل البناية
including the air conditioning ducts.
حتى قنوات التكييف
I hired guys who paint flats
قمت بتوظيف أشخاص مختصين بطلاء الشقق
fixed on the sides of garages
مثبتين على جوانب الكراجات
to do the painting on the building, and they loved it.
ليقوموا بطلاء البناية وأحبوها
They got into it -- they took the job incredibly seriously.
انهمكوا في العملية وأخذوا الأمر بجدية على عاتقهم
They used to climb up on the building and call me
اعتادوا على تسلق البناية ومناداتي
and tell me that they had to correct my typography --
ليخبروني أنه علي أن أصحح الخط
that my spacing was wrong, and they moved it,
أن الفراغات كانت غير سليمة وقاموا بتحريكها
and they did wonderful things with it.
وقاموا بأشياء جميلة
They were pretty serious, too. It was quite wonderful.
كانوا جادين وكان الأمر رائعا
By the time I did Bloomberg's headquarters
في الوقت الذي أنجزت فيه مقر بلومبيرغ
my work had begun to become accepted.
بدأ عملي يصبح مقبولا
People wanted it in big, expensive places.
وأراد الناس الحصول عليه في أماكن باهظة
And that began to make it solemn.
وهذا جعل العمل رصينا
Bloomberg was all about numbers,
كان تصميم بلومبيرغ متمحورا حول الأرقام
and we did big numbers through the space
وقمنا برسم أرقام كبيرة على المبنى
and the numbers were projected on a spectacular LED
وكانت الأرقام معروضة على شاشة ليد خلابة
that my partner, Lisa Strausfeld, programmed.
قامت ببرمجتها شريكتي ليزا ستراوسفيلد
But it became the end
لكنها كانت النهاية
of the seriousness of the play,
نهاية اللعب الجاد
and it started to, once again, become solemn.
وأصبح العمل رصينا مرة أخرى
This is a current project
هذا مشروع حديث
in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania,
في بيتسبيرغ، بينسلفانيا
where I got to be goofy.
حيث استطعت أن أكون حمقاء
I was invited to design
كنت مدعوة لأصمم
a logo for this neighborhood, called the North Side,
شعارا لهذا الحي الذي يدعى الحي الشمالي
and I thought it was silly for a neighborhood to have a logo.
وكنت أعتقد أنه من السخافة أن يكون هنالك شعار لحي معين
I think that's rather creepy, actually. Why would a neighborhood have a logo?
أعتقد أن هذا مخيف في الواقع، لماذا يجب أن يكون هنالك للحي شعار؟
A neighborhood has a thing -- it's got a landmark, it's got a place,
الحي يملك أماكن معينة
it's got a restaurant. It doesn't have a logo. I mean, what would that be?
مطعما، لا شعارا. أعني، كيف سيكون شكل هذا الشعار؟
So I had to actually give a presentation
لذا كان علي أن أقدم عرضا تقديميا
to a city council
لمجلس المدينة
and neighborhood constituents,
وبلديات الحي
and I went to Pittsburgh and I said,
ذهبت إلى بيتسبيرغ وقلت:
"You know, really what you have here
هل تعلمون أن لديكم هنا
are all these underpasses
الكثير من الممرات السفلية للسيارات؟
that separate the neighborhood from the center of town.
التي تفصل الحي عن مركز المدينة
Why don't you celebrate them, and make the underpasses landmarks?"
لم لا تحتفلون بها وتجعلوا منها المعلم الرئيسي؟
So I began doing this crazy presentation
بدأت أعمل هذا العرض المجنون
of these installations --
لهذه الهياكل
potential installations -- on
هياكل محتملة
these underpass bridges,
على الجسور السفلية
and stood up in front of the city council --
ووقفت أمام مجلس المدينة
and was a little bit scared,
وكنت متخوفة قليلا
I have to admit.
هذا ما أعترف به
But I was so utterly unqualified for this project,
لكنني كنت غير مؤهلة للعمل في هذا المشروع
and so utterly ridiculous,
وكنت سخيفة إلى أبعد حد
and ignored the brief so desperately
وتجاهلت التقديم تماما
that I think they just embraced it with wholeheartedness,
وهذا ما جعلهم يقتنعون بتقديمي
just completely because it was so goofy to begin with.
لأنه كان مليئا بالحماقة
And this is the bridge they're actually
هذا هو الجسر الذي في الواقع
painting up and preparing as we speak.
يقومون بطلائه ويعدونه في هذه اللحظة
It will change every six months, and it will become an art installation
سيتغير كل ستة أشهر وسيصبح بناء فنيا
in the North Side of Pittsburgh,
في الجانب الشمالي من بيتسبيرغ
and it will probably become a landmark in the area.
وربما سيصبح معلما في هذه المنطقة
John Hockenberry told you a bit about
أخبركم جون هوكينبيري قليلا عن
my travail with Citibank,
اتفاقي مع سيتي بنك
that is now a 10-year relationship, and I still work with them.
العلاقة الآن أمدها عشرة سنوات ولا أزال أعمل معهم
And I actually am amused by them and like them,
وفي الواقع أنا أحبهم
and think that as a very, very, very, very, very big corporation
وأعتقد أنهم كمؤسسة كبيرة كبيرة جدا
they actually keep their graphics very nice.
فإن رسوماتهم جميلة جدا
I drew the logo for Citibank
أنا صممت شعار سيتي بنك
on a napkin in the first meeting.
على محرمة ورقية في الاجتماع الأول
That was the play part of the job.
هذا كان جانب اللعب في الوظيفة
And then I spent a year
ثم أمضيت عاما
going to long, tedious,
انخرطت فيه في اجتماعات طويلة ومرهقة
boring meetings,
ومملة
trying to sell this logo through
كنت أحاول فيها أن أبيعهم هذا الشعار
to a huge corporation
للمؤسسة الكبيرة
to the point of tears.
إلى حد أنني كنت أذرف الدموع
I thought I was going to go crazy at the end of this year.
وكنت أعتقد أنني سأجن بنهاية السنة
We made idiotic presentations
قمنا بعمل عروض بلهاء
showing how the Citi logo made sense,
نبين فيه كيف أن شعار سيتي بنك كان ذا مغزى
and how it was really derived from an umbrella,
وكيف كانت فكرته منبثقة من مظلة
and we made animations of these things,
وقمنا بعمل صور متحركة لهذا التصميم
and we came back and forth and back and forth and back and forth.
وكنا نحرز تقدما وتراجعا مرات عديدة
And it was worth it, because they bought this thing,
وكان الأمر يستحق العناء لأنهم اشتروا الشعار
and it played out on such a grand scale,
وأصبح شائعا على نطاق كبير
and it's so internationally recognizable,
ومعروفا على نطاق عالمي
but for me it was actually a very, very depressing year.
لكن بالنسبة لي كان عاما محبطا جدا
As a matter of fact, they actually never bought onto the logo
وفي حقيقة الأمر لم يقتنعوا بالشعار تماما
until Fallon put it on
لغاية قيام فالون بوضعه
its very good "Live Richly" campaign,
في حملتها "العيش بثراء"
and then everybody accepted it all over the world.
وعندها تقبل العالم الشعار
So during this time I needed
لذا خلال هذا الوقت
some kind of counterbalance
احتجت إلى موازنة
for this crazy, crazy existence
هذا التواجد المجنون
of going to these long, idiotic meetings.
والاجتماعات البلهاء الطويلة
And I was up in my country house,
وكنت في منزلي الريفي
and for some reason, I began painting
لسبب ما بدأت بالرسم
these very big, very involved,
رسمت خرائط كبيرة جدا
laborious, complicated
ومعقدة
maps of the entire world,
للعالم
and listing every place on the planet, and putting them in,
وبدأت أدرج كل مكان على الأرض في الخرائط
and misspelling them, and putting things in the wrong spot,
وأخطأ في كتابتها وأضع أشياء في المكان الخطأ
and completely controlling the information,
وأتحكم بالمعلومات
and going totally and completely nuts with it.
وأرسم بجنون
They would take me about six months initially,
استغرقت مني ستة أشهر ابتداء
but then I started getting faster at it.
ثم بدأت أصبح أسرع
Here's the United States.
ها هي الولايات المتحدة
Every single city of the United States is on here.
كل مدينة فيها موجودة هنا
And it hung for about eight months
وعلقتها لثمانية أشهر
at the Cooper-Hewitt, and people walked up to it,
في كوبر-هيويت وبدأ الناس يسيرون لرؤيتها
and they would point to a part of the map
وبدأوا يشيرون إلى جزء من الخريطة
and they'd say, "Oh, I've been here."
ويقولوا: "آه أنا كنت هنا"
And, of course, they couldn't have been because it's in the wrong spot.
وطبعا هذا ليس صحيحا لأن الأماكن موضوعة في الأماكن الخاطئة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But what I liked about it was,
لكن ما أحببته في هذا
I was controlling my own idiotic information,
أنني كنت أتحكم بمعلوماتي البلهاء
and I was creating my own palette of information,
وكنت أبتكر صحيفتي من المعلومات
and I was totally and completely
وكنت منهمكة تماما وكليا
at play.
في اللعب
One of my favorites was
وكان من بين الرسومات المفضلة لي
this painting I did of Florida after the 2000 election
هذه اللوحة التي قمت برسمها لفلوريدا بعد انتخابات عام 2000
that has the election results rolling around in the water.
وتبدو فيها نتائج الانتخابات مرمية في الماء
I keep that for evidence.
احتفظت بذلك كدليل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Somebody
كان هنالك
was up at my house and saw the paintings
شخص ما في منزلي ورأى اللوحة
and recommended them to a gallery,
واقترح أن أضعها في معرض
and I had a first show
وحظيت بمعرضي الأول
about two-and-a-half years ago, and I showed these paintings
قبل حوالي عامين ونصف وعرضت فيه هذه اللوحات
that I'm showing you now.
التي أعرضها عليكم الآن
And then a funny thing happened -- they sold.
ثم حدث شيء مضحك- حيث بيعت هذه اللوحات
And they sold quickly,
وبيعت بسرعة كبيرة
and became rather popular.
وأصبحت شائعة
We started making prints from them.
بدأنا نصنع نسخ عنها
This is Manhattan, one from the series.
هذه منهاتن إحدى لوحات المجموعة
This is a print from the United States which we did in red, white and blue.
هذه لوحة للولايات المتحدة باللون الأحمر والأبيض والأزرق
We began doing these big silkscreen prints,
بدأنا بصنع لوحات كبيرة من الحرير
and they started selling, too.
وبدأنا نبيعها كذلك
So, the gallery wanted me to have another show
لذا طلب المعرض مني اقامة عرض آخر
in two years,
خلال عامين
which meant that I really
مما يعني بأنني
had to paint these paintings
كنت مضطرة لرسم هذه اللوحات
much faster
بسرعة أكبر
than I had ever done them. And I --
من ذي قبل وبدأت
they started to become more political, and I picked areas
أصبح سياسية أكثر واخترت مناطق
that sort of were in the news
كانت تذاع أخبارها
or that I had some feeling about,
أو كان لدي شعور تجاهها
and I began doing these things.
وبدأت أرسم هذه اللوحات
And then this funny thing happened.
ثم حدث شيء غريب
I found that I was no longer at play.
اكتشفت أنني لا أنخرط في اللعب
I was actually in this solemn landscape
كنت في لحظة رصانة
of fulfilling an expectation
تنتظر مني انجاز شيء معين
for a show,
لمعرض
which is not where I started with these things.
وهذا ما لم يكن السبب الذي بدأت من أجله بتصميم هذه الأشياء
So, while they became successful,
ولذا عندما أصبحت رائجة
I know how to make them,
وعرفت كيف أصممها
so I'm not a neophyte,
لم أكن مبتدئة
and they're no longer serious --
ولم تصبح جادة
they have become solemn.
أصبحت رصينة
And that's a terrifying factor --
وهذا عامل مخيف
when you start something and it turns that way --
عندما تبدأ شيء معين ويصبح رصينا
because it means that all that's left for you
لأن ذلك يعني بأن كل ما تبقى لك
is to go back and to find out
هو أن تعود وتجد ذلك الشيء
what the next thing is that you can push,
تجد ما الشيء التالي الذي تستطيع أن تبتكره
that you can invent, that you can be ignorant about,
الذي يمكنك أن تكون غير مكترثا بشأنه
that you can be arrogant about,
وأن تكون متغطرسا بشأنه
that you can fail with,
يمكنك أن تخفق فيه
and that you can be a fool with.
ويمكنك أن تكون أبلها معه
Because in the end, that's how you grow,
لأن في نهاية المطاف هذا هو الأسلوب الذي تكبر من خلاله
and that's all that matters.
وهذا ما يهم
So, I'm plugging along here --
لذا سأختتم محاضرتي عند هذا الحد
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and I'm just going to have to blow up the staircase.
وما سأفعله هو أنني سأقوم بنسف السلم
Thank you very much.
شكرا لكم.